<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cultures Across Cultures</title>
    <description>An eight month journey to understand how we relate to microbes, and how they interact with each other.
</description>
    <link>/cultureshttp://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/cultures/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:46:28 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:46:28 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>France Week 2-4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi again, it’s been a while! I have been trying to find the balance between living in the moment and documenting everything. After a few weeks, the amount of content I needed to catch up on was daunting, so I neglected the blog a bit. Here’s a review of weeks 2-4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;france-week-2&quot;&gt;France week 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my first few samples, email responses started rolling in, and I found this week to be the most productive for my project. I thank everyone who kindly welcomed me into their lives, and want to share a few highlights here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought in cheese from the farmers market (samples 1-8) because I simply had too much for one gal to eat. My prof, Dr. Jean-Yves Bouet, kindly went to get a few baguettes and labmates enjoyed the haul throughout the day. There was a group meeting that Monday, so I presented a few slides about my background and project to the team. While the meeting is normally in French, all the team-members have a professional working level of English, which saved me the embarrassment of sounding like an 8-year-old trying to speak in French. While the team consists of experts in the field of genome dynamics and plasmid partitioning, they gave such helpful information about cheese regulations in France. The Institut national de la recherche agronomique, or INRA, has a large focus on understanding fermented dairy diversity across the country. INRA recently merged with another national research institute, IRSTEA, to create INRAE, or Institut national de recherche pour l’agriculture, l’alimentation et l’environnement. They have an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.france-genomique.org/projet/metapdocheese/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ongoing study&lt;/a&gt; to create metagenomic and gene expression databases of protected French cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1411, France has protected the production of many of its food products, ranging from olive oil to lavender to cheese. These products often have long-established histories in geographical areas and cannot be labelled under the same name if produced outside of that area. Terroir is an all-encompassing term for soil, environment, and climate in a specific region that can influence how a product turns out. In France, products were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inao.gouv.fr/content/download/1904/19595/version/1/file/INAO%20-%20fiches%20signes%20-%20UK%20-%20AOC%20AOP%20-%20BD.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;designated as protected&lt;/a&gt; under Appellation d’Origine Contrôlée (AOC), which has now become Appellation d’Origine Protégée (AOP). This means when you go to buy a Bordeux wine or slice of Roquefort cheese, it will have an AOP label on it. Europe-wide, the label is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inao.gouv.fr/eng/Official-signs-identifying-quality-and-origin/PDO-AOC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PDO&lt;/a&gt;, or Protected Designation of Origin. There are about 46 cheeses and 300 wines that hold this designation. While I had a vague idea of France protecting “Champagne”, I did not know the depth of agricultural protections present in the country. Once day, I was showing my graduation photos to a lab mate and came across the classic “champagne spraying” photo. I explained the American celebration tradition of spraying “champagne” and she quickly corrected me, “No, no. That is just sparkling wine”. She was right, it was $5 bottle of Rosé from Ralphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After group meeting, I completed my first 9 extractions, with the last sample being Dr. Bouet’s home-grown kefir. The protocol is very straight-forward and takes about 2 hours to complete, from weighing out the samples to having DNA in hand. Here’s an over-bench view of me adding Solution CD2, which precipitates non-DNA material like cell debris, polysaccharides, and proteins. This is the first step in purifying the DNA after releasing it from bacterial and fungal cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Extraction&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I presented my goal of finding local, unpasteurized cheese samples, Prof. Bouet referred me to Anthony, owner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lalaiterietoulousaine.fr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;La Laiterie Toulousaine&lt;/a&gt;. Anthony is a true expert of his craft and a former engineer. He consciously collects milk from farms in the area, usually leaving at 4 in the morning so he can be back in time to make cheese with the fresh milk that day. Anthony graciously spent a few hours explaining his processes and taught me much about the microbiological regulations that French cheesemakers must follow. Raw milk consumption and raw milk cheeses are declining across the country because every few years, there is a &lt;em&gt;Listeria&lt;/em&gt; outbreak, usually disproportionately affecting children. The Institut de l’Elevage, through European and French regulatory collaboration, created a set of guidelines for maximum quantities of key microbes in all dairy products, from raw milk to ice cream. In some cases, these are extremely specific to the time of production (pre or post-fermentation, for example), but one finding is clear. &lt;em&gt;Listeria monocytogenes&lt;/em&gt; should be absent in every product except raw milk. Then, it is permissible up to 100 cfu per milliliter. I think this is interesting because it acknowledges the fact that &lt;em&gt;Listeria monocytogenes&lt;/em&gt; may be present at low levels in raw milk, but cheese and yogurt fermentation should provide the environment for this bacteria to be outcompeted by other microbes, either from starter or those present in the milk already. I am excited to look into this further, as I collected several raw milk samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Anthony&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The burden falls on the local artisan cheesemaker to ensure their process is hygenic and does not promote growth of &lt;em&gt;L monocytogenes, E. coli&lt;/em&gt; coliforms, or &lt;em&gt;Salmonella&lt;/em&gt; past acceptable limits. Anthony submits his cheeses for culture-based testing when needed, but was excited to learn specifically what microbes were in his samples. Because he hosts frequent cheese workshops, he will be able to tell visitors which bacteria and yeast are present in what they are making. I find this to be one of the most rewarding parts of my project. Time and time again, I met local producers who pour their heart and soul into sourcing milks, developing cheese recipes, and optimizing their production. So many of them had a deep interest in the microbiology of what they were spending their days making. However, collecting and understanding microbial composition data can be time-consuming and expensive. I hope they find our conversations at the time of sampling and when I send them their data fulfilling and useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Collection setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collected 16 samples from Anthony, jotting down as much information as I could about the starters, type of milk, and aging process. When possible, I took samples from the rind and the inside of the cheese. Later that week, I was able to collect time-course cheese samples starting from raw milk he collected that morning from a farm in Montauban. My collection method got a little more sophisticated than ziploc bags thanks to some cardboard, tape, and screw-top tubes from lab. While we were discussing raw milk, Anthony pointed me in the direction of a few papers circling the cheese community in France. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-020-1095-x?proof=t2019-11-4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;One paper&lt;/a&gt; discusses the potential of raw milk in early childhood to reduce asthma through metabolites produced by gut microbes. Recently, pathogen risks and high costs of raw milk have caused an industrial and regulatory movement towards pasteurization. Last year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/travel/article/20180618-the-end-to-a-french-cheese-traditionchanged&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AOP for Camembert&lt;/a&gt; changed to allow pastuerized milk, much to the dismay of small producers and farmers in the region. Surely microbes present in Normandy cow milk contribute to the terroir of this cheese, so the ongoing debate about AOP in relation to microbes is interesting to keep tabs on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Taste of Toulouse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That week, I also met up with Jessica from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tasteoftoulouse.com/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Taste of Toulouse&lt;/a&gt; food tours, who was kind enough to show me around her favorite cheese shops in town. We went to Xavier Fromagerie, and I sampled some of their famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://xavier.fr/en/produit/Le-Pave-Toulousain-Affinage-12-mois&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pavé Toulousain&lt;/a&gt;. Jessica explained that the modern cube shape of the cheese represents Toulouse’s efforts towards technology advancement, as well as mimicking the brick structures common in town. She showed me around Victor Hugo Market, which is a local favorite featuring dozens of food vendors. From Fromagerie Emilie, I sampled a couple of hard cheeses just one farm away from each other in Ariege. I took a sample of raw crème fraîche from Deux Chavanne. Jessica also had a few recommendations for other spots in town, which I went to the next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Moloko&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, I went to Mokolo, a bar in Carmes, with Prof. Bouet’s daughter, Leah, and her two friends from school. It was so interesting learning about their lives growing up in France, and their impressions about the US. I was happy to share my food recommendations for New York with them in exchange for their favorite bakeries in town. It is easy to forget how big of a role the US plays in global media, politics, and culture, when I usually only engage with domestic news at home. When I do read international news, it’s through the New York Times or other US-based companies. They grew up having a deep understanding and appreciation for local, national, European, and international affairs. Most of the TV and music they listen to is from the US. During our conversation, I found myself feeling the sudden urge to read up on global news as soon as I got home. But the kind of knowledge they had wasn’t just from keeping up on US headlines, they were aware of and curious about American culture. It was wonderful to share what I could about my background, but I honestly felt like a naive tourist when most of what I knew about their culture came from my French class, Emily in Paris, and barely 2 weeks of living there. I felt no passing of judgment, which I was grateful for, but it made me realize how much there was to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To round off a wonderful week, Prof. Bouet graciously invited me to his family home, showed me their gardens, and we walked along the Canal du Midi, a UNESCO World Heritage site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Canal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;france-week-3&quot;&gt;France week 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first farm visit! &lt;a href=&quot;https://fermedubila.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;La Ferme du Bila&lt;/a&gt; graciously welcomed me to their farm. I took a 6 AM train out of Toulouse, and they picked me up after dropping their kids off at school. Emilie gave me a detailed tour of their cheese-making facilities, which she designed on her own after visiting and learning from many others in the area (and at a cheese shop near Niagara Falls, where she trained!). I got to meet their goats, which they feed from grains grown on their farm. They started off with a few goats several years ago, but now raise the baby goats each year, so no new animals enter the farm. A closed-loop system! At points during the year, if the goats have lower milk production, they sell some of the grains they harvest as well. While the starter she uses is industrial, she passages it for a few months, using a little at the end of each passage. This can give rise to some interesting evolutionary dynamics, so I was interested to take some samples from different stages in the aging process. Emilie and her husband were very welcoming and open in telling me about their story. The farm has been in his family for at least 500 years. The time scale is absolutely astonishing to me considering I have not ever lived in the same house for more than 5 years. They kindly drove me back into Toulouse as they were heading in to buy holiday presents for their boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img7.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Emilie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baptiste from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/boulangerie_maurice/?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Boulangerie Maurice&lt;/a&gt;, which Jessica recommended, was so excited about the science! We spent a few hours discussing his process, which emphasizes natural fermentation and non-industrialized methods. To this end, he hand-kneads all of his dough (you have to check out the videos to believe it). He started his bakery a few years ago as a third career. His starter, named Maurice, is only fed with top tier wild 40 grain flour from a nearby farm. Baptiste knows his starter probably more than most people know their best friend. Just by touch, he knows when Maurice is hungry, and can tune the humidity, water level, and temperature, to get the happiest starter needed to make dozens of delicious loaves of bread per day. In the past, Baptiste has shared Maurice with friends, and shared that it takes about three months for sourdough starter to change in consistency, texture, and taste, when exposed to any new environment. I would like to analyze this further, because my hunch is that the microbes start changing immediately. As we were discussing, customers filtered in, grabbing their loaf or a sourdough chocolate chip cookie to go. Baptiste spent a few minutes catching up with the regulars before shifting right back to explaining acidity during sourdough fermentation to me. Together, we planned a few experiments. I took sourdough in the morning, and after a few hours of fermentation. I also took swabs of his wooden kneading station and his hands to see if we can detect microbe transfer between the surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Baptiste&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last sample collection in Toulouse was from Prof. Helene Tormo at École d’Ingénieurs de Purpan. I got in touch with her from one of the professors at CBI Toulouse. Prof. Tormo is a leader in dairy microbiology, and collected a couple of Pelardon samples for me from local farmers she was in contact with. I am realizing this post is slowly turning into selfies with all of the cool people I met this week, and that’s ok! One of my favorite parts of Watson has been meeting people from different backgrounds, hearing about their lives, and learning about what they are excited about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Helene&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrapped up the week by finishing extractions and getting my samples ready to ship to Switzerland. It was December 17th, and ETH Zurich had already started holiday. CBI Toulouse was going to be mostly on holiday for the next few weeks, so I discussed with someone in lab to arrange shipment of my samples in January – more on that in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I also went to the movies to watch Spiderman: No Way Home, a whole two days before it was released in the US! I must say, it was a bit of a challenge because the movie theater was much stricter regarding COVID vaccination than any restaurants or stores. While vaccination was not mandatory in France at the time, you had to show proof of vaccination to enter any indoor establishment. In the EU, they have a fancy QR code that some people even had as their phone screensaver because they had to scan it so often. I, on the other hand, have an awkwardly sized piece of paper from the CDC with the handwritten date and brand of doses. The California QR code didn’t work – I tried. At the beginning, I was carrying a photo of my vaccine card, but one cafe asked me to see the original document, so I got in the habit of bringing the actual card with me everywhere. I kept it in a ziploc sandwich bag for super secure waterproofing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there I am, waiting in line at the Gaumont Capitole movie theater to pass the security checkpoint. There is one burly man at the entrance scanning the QR codes. I finally reach the front, hand him my plastic bagged piece of paper, and he does not look impressed. He stares at it for a few seconds, then starts asking me questions in French. I ask if he speaks English, but he shakes his head and we reach a stalemate. He grabs his walkie talkie and calls for more help because there are at least 15 people behind me waiting to see the Spiderman premiere. Nobody seems keen to help out, so the security guy waves me to the side and keeps scanning people in. A few minutes pass, the line gets even longer despite the steady stream entering, and English-speaking backup is nowhere in sight. So I stand awkwardly for a few minutes then try to show the guy my card again, pleading in my broken French that I am vaccinated and boosted. He responds in a stern tone, shaking his head. I felt so embarrassed seeing all the locals breeze by me without a hitch, seemingly laughing at the tourist who couldn’t speak French. After a few more minutes of trying to discuss with him, I called it quits and walked home, cheeks bright red in shame. Why was I crying over not getting to see a movie? Why couldn’t I be more assertive? Why couldn’t I speak French?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, this was one of my lowest points of my Watson so far. And I am sure it sounds silly and unbelievably privileged to be upset over a movie. For me, though, this interaction felt reminiscent of a lot of the broader challenges I was facing. Let me rewind a bit here. At this point, I had no set plan on where to go after France. My next country, Iceland, was still on level 4. My country for February, Finland, was on holiday until the last week of January. They also rose to level 4 around this time, along with almost the entire world. I sent some emails to labs in a few countries that were level 3: Ghana, India, Kenya, and Indonesia. Sweden was the only European country still on level 3, but with how omicron was progressing, I had a hunch it would rise soon. It seems that the US Travel Advisory mainly takes case counts into consideration, rather than hospital availability or medical access in the event of infection. I understand perceived risk very much depends on the person, but for knowing myself and my travel experience, I would feel less safe in Sierra Leone (level 2) than Finland (level 4). I struggle with understanding how much of this is due to my biased perceptions versus objective facts about the countries. The truth is I don’t know much about West Africa as a whole. I would like to learn more, and break down any incorrect stereotypes I hold about safety there. I came to the conclusion that traveling alone during a pandemic to Ghana or Kenya for the first time was not in the cards for me. I started to feel so lost at this time. I had no concrete plans for where I would be 10 days in the future, and it felt like my life was being decided by the US Government’s RNG of COVID advisories. Maybe that sounds like a burly security man telling you whether or not you can see a movie, or maybe it doesn’t. But when I was walking back from the movie theater, I was thinking if I spoke French fluently, I could spend January in smaller towns where English is less common. If I was more assertive with why I thought the US Travel Advisory was a poor indication of COVID risk, maybe I could convince the Watson committee that level 4 was OK. And if I wasn’t alone, I could easily explain how I felt to my friends or family without sounding like a petulant who couldn’t go see a movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth, I went back later and the security woman waved me through without a second glance at the paper vaccine card. And the movie was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend enjoying Toulouse as a tourist. The local museum hosted a large display of birds, bugs, and bones in the biodiversity section. Their botanical gardens were wonderful, especially the tropical plants room. Heated to a toasty 78F, it was the coziest and warmest I had felt since arriving in France. There were comics scattered around the museum as well, and dare I say that they drew a bacterial cell as one of the 10 things that have changed the world? I can only guess what the silhouettes are meant to represent. I also highly recommend the local aerospace museum. Airbus France is headquartered in Toulouse, and there is a rich history of aviation in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;france-week-4&quot;&gt;France week 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cheese and dairy farmers had wrapped up production for the season and kicked into high gear to sell the last of the year’s products for holiday meals or gifts. With no lab access for the rest of my time in France, I was deciding whether to stay in town or explore more. One of my good friends got me these fun match-stick adventure starters before I left on my Watson, and I like to pick one every once in a while. I ended up with this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img11.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Stick&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I am a very organized, planning-oriented person. I like to make a schedule and stick to it. This helped me with managing my research and homework in undergrad, but part of the reason I applied to the Watson was to learn to live without a plan. Going into my Watson, I knew there would be situations where I would learn something that would change my path forward. I wanted to be open to these changes and learn to adapt to them as they came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there I was holding the adventure matchstick. I decided to go on an impromptu backpacking trip around the South of France. I did a couple of hours of research, then hopped on an afternoon train to &lt;a href=&quot;https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/345/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carcassonne&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most stunning places I have ever been (and inspiration for a board game!). I arrived about an hour before sunset, dropped my backpack off at the hostel, and sped-walked up the hill to the walled fortress. You can freely wander among the roads, feeling like a villager or royal from the 13th century. The modern side of town was very festive, and I enjoyed the local Christmas market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img12.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Carcassonne&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I took an early train to Collioure, which came highly recommended by Jean-Yves, my professor at CBI Toulouse. I had tentatively planned on going to Montpellier after spending a few hours in Collioure, but it was too beautiful to leave so soon. I explored the Château Royal de Collioure, which had open tunnels running through the castle. I hiked to Fort Saint Elme, then meandered around town in the evening. Most of the stores and restaurants are seasonal, so it felt a little deserted. I enjoyed the lack of tourists and took the time to peacefully journal along the waterfront. I reflected on what was important to me, how much I felt I had grown in the past month, and planned for the end of the month a bit more. I decided I wanted to spend Christmas in Paris, and probably would find a cheaper international flight out of there than Toulouse. That meant I should be back in Toulouse three days from that point to pack up and move out of my place there. I made the tentative plan for a day in Cassis and Aix-en-Provence, then transit back to Toulouse to wrap up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img13.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Collioure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another early rise to take a 6 AM train to Marseille, then the M8 bus to Cassis, a nearby fishing town close to the Calanques National Park. I had about 5 hours until sundown, so I planned on a few mile stroll to see the first and second Calanques (Port Miou and Port Pin). I dropped off my bag and water at the hotel, only bringing my phone and still wearing my heavy down parka. Now, I have done quite a bit of hiking in California, but the views throughout the Calanques are unlike anything I have experienced before. There are ample look-out points to gaze at where the crisp blue Mediterranean sea meets the stark white limestone. The whole afternoon felt like a dream. I ended up hiking to the third Calanque (d’En-vau), which was strenuous and rocky. Once I got to the rocky beach and dipped my toes in the water, all my stresses about where I would live in eight days just melted away. I spent as much time there as I could before I had to head back while it was still light out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Calanques&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, I started talking to a wonderful newlywed couple from India. I had a great time exchanging stories, learning their wedding was bigger than the entire undergrad population of Caltech, and graciously accepting their offer to drive me back to town and buy me dinner. Thank you Prerak and Devanshee, come visit Boston anytime!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Calanques&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the same bus back to Marseille, then the L50 to Aix-en-Provence. This was probably the most posh of the French towns I visited. While journaling at a cafe during lunch, the man at the table next to me asked what I was writing. I ended up talking to him and his daughter, a PhD student in Paris, for almost an hour. Traveling alone can be isolating at times, but it often opens doors to meet new people. If I had been entrenched in a conversation with someone, I would have never heard about his and his daughter’s lives in Aix-en-Provence and Paris. On my way out, I accidentally knocked over my water glass and instantly felt beyond embarrassed. The waiter just laughed it off. He told me, “I don’t know how to say it well in English, but my mom always said”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you never do anything, then you will never make any stupid mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;cite&gt;La Cabane en Ville's Waiter's mom&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, waiter man, I think that will now be my motto for pushing myself to try new things this year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20220131/img16.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Aix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Christmas Eve, I took a BlaBlaCar back to Toulouse, which is basically a long-distance Uber Pool. I got to meet three people who were heading home for the holidays, and shared my story with them. It is always funny to hear the reactions when I explain the Watson. It probably depends on how I explain it, but some people are interested to hear more about my research, or traveling during COVID, or how I make friends when traveling alone. To answer the last one, if I don’t meet friends through a mutual pal, my second go-to is asking people if they want me to take a photo of them. Hopefully not in a creepy way and only if I see them struggling to center the castle or Christmas tree or fountain into the background of their selfie. Usually people offer to take one of me afterwards, and then occasionally a conversation strikes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap&quot;&gt;Wrap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent my final evening in Toulouse, feeling a little nostalgic about how quickly the time passed and hoping that I will visit again someday. I hope you enjoyed reading, learned something, or both. If you have any questions, notes, or found a typo, please feel free to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will cover my week in Paris (probably in less detail than this), and my month in India in future posts. Sending positivity wherever you are!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cultures/2022/01/31/france-wrap-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cultures/2022/01/31/france-wrap-up/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Week</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;entering-france&quot;&gt;Entering France&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two layovers, one in Atlanta and another in Paris. To board both flights, I had to show a copy of my vaccination card and passport. However, I did not realize that immigration checks take place in the first city in a new country, even if connecting through. So, with my 75 minute connection at CDG airport, I barely had enough time to make it through security and passport check. At CDG security, I got pulled aside for having 4-inch long scissors that I forgot to put in my checked bag, oops. Surprisingly these did not get confiscated by US security. As a result of this, my bag and shoes also got swabbed for explosive testing. After making it through, I was surprised that there were no additional customs to go through once I landed in Toulouse. I did not get a passport stamp or need to show any proof of how long I was staying, sufficient funds, or a return flight (though I had booked a refundable flight to Iceland in case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;settling-in&quot;&gt;Settling in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I landed in Toulouse in the afternoon and took a local bus to my studio. Check-in at the Airbnb was a breeze. After dropping off my bags, I took a walk around City Centre, which is completely decked out for the holidays. String lights line almost every offshoot from the Capitole, all the way to the Garonne river. The Capitole itself is set up for the Marché de Noël, which is a Christmas market similar to Bryant Park during the Holidays. They require the Pass Sanitaire, which is a QR code required for most indoor or crowded public spaces in France. Non-EU nationals can apply for this at pharmacies with a physical vaccination card. While near Capitole, I stopped at the post office to buy international stamps (to my family: check your mail soon)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;City at night&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my walk back, I stopped at an ATM to pick up some Euros to have on hand. This was a better exchange rate than if I had ordered currency from a bank in the US. I also stopped at Monop, a supermarket, to pick up some essentials and scope out the yogurt section. I also must say I have never seen a jar of nutella (10.50 Euros per kg) selling for cheaper than a jar of peanut butter (15.44 Euros per kg). What’s a girl to do, bring nutella and jelly sandwiches to lab?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I should probably mention I don’t speak much French. I can understand more than I can speak. Even so, hearing the language spoken in an audio exercise from a textbook is very different than standing in line at a market, with five people behind you, puzzled about whether the cashier is asking you if you need a receipt or a bag. I think Merci, Pardon, and Ça va have been doing some good work for me, but I hope my time here will expand my knowledge of the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Yogurt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-the-lab&quot;&gt;Meeting the Lab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a day recovering, but I had gotten over jet lag quickly (or so I thought). On Thursday, I woke up and headed down to Jean-Jaurès metro station, which is just across the street from my studio. It was going to be a 20 minute ride and 7 minute walk to lab, but I left an hour early because I was excited to explore and meet the group. On my way to the metro station, I stopped at La Mie de Pain, and got a chocolate croissant (for only one Euro!). I stashed the croissant for my walk, and entered the metro station. There were self-service kiosks but I was bold and wanted to test out my French, so I walked into the Tisséo office. Through the mask and plastic barrier, I could barely hear the agent and think I asked her to “pouvez-vous répéter” at least seven times. For one month of unlimited public transport at my age, the cost was 8 Euros for the Pastel card and 16 Euros for the transit itself. For verified French students, transit is free! Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img4.jpeg#full&quot; alt=&quot;CBI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metro cars were understandably busy for a weekday morning, but the bulk of the passengers (including me) disembarked at the University’s three stops. I found the Centre de Biologie Intégrative after enjoying a stroll through campus enjoying my croissant. I met up with Prof. Jean-Yves Bouet, co-lead of the Genome Dynamics (GeDy) team, who showed me around his lab. There are ample GeDy / Jedi posters showing the team merged onto Star Wars scenes, and the space is quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers at CBI are appointed through the CNRS, or France’s state science agency. It is Europe’s largest fundamental science agency. I found Prof. Bouet through CBI’s website, where his research in bacterial chromosome organization and plasmid segregation piqued my interest. After chatting with him on zoom in November, he shared that he is an avid kefir fermenter (I’ll be sampling this next week!) The other researchers in the group were all very welcoming, and, while I tried to avoid this feeling, it was comforting to speak English with someone for the first time in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chatted with Prof. Bouet about French PhD programs. During the conversation, he mentioned he did his PhD there, in the very building he now leads a group in. Usually French PhD programs are three years, with no rotations, and projects are assigned upon admission. We discussed how, while the expedited time frame can be beneficial, it runs the risk of not giving enough time for a student to fully develop different aspects of a project. Lengthier US PhD programs give students time to develop ideas and, well, fail more. Failure is a part of science and running into roadblocks early on can help scientists learn how to overcome challenges. Especially during COVID, Prof. Bouet says, it was hard for students to get enough lab time to finish within their funding timeline. Having a sharp deadline to graduate during a pandemic posed definite challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent some time marvelling about how sequencing is so prevalent that many young researchers (myself included) sometimes do not take the time to revel in the wonder of it. We can ship DNA in the mail. The next day, we can see letters on our screen. Prof. Bouet shared his experience sequencing one of the key genes in T4. He worked his way in from the ends of the 3.5 kb segment. After every PCR, he had to order new primers just to keep being able to PCR inward. For something that would take less than 24 hours today, Prof. Bouet had to spend three months on it. And that was quick for the time, because the University had in-house oligo synthesis. Stories like these put the techniques we have today into perspective. Me, and other scientists around my age, will not know the burden of trying to hack our way through PCR sequencing or compiling our code by hand. But then again, professors today do not know the burden of mouth pipetting (I hope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day, there was a seminar hosted by a researcher retiring from CBI. I meant to go on Zoom – the talks sounded interesting – but when I got home, I fell asleep for a while. And thus began the vicious cycle of sleeping from 4-6 PM, 11 PM-1 AM, and 7 AM - 11 AM. I might have finally kicked that schedule, but I will have to see it to believe it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-the-project-moving-again&quot;&gt;Getting The Project Moving Again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next two days exhausted from the strange sleep schedule, and started to feel guilty for just being at home. It feels surreal to be in a new city, alone, with so much to see and explore, but all I could do was read, watch Netflix (which still has Friends in France!), and go for walks along the river. Dusk at the Garonne River has been one of the most serene times for me to reflect. Here’s something I wrote Friday night after reading the (very interesting) plaques along the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Garonne&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I sit on the bank of the Garonne. To my left is the Pont-Neuf, or new bridge, named so because it is relatively new, built in the 16th century. I am looking ahead at the Hôtel-Dieu Saint-Jacques, a lovely pair of buildings from 1257. They look like some ancient fortress ready to receive ships along the water, but instead they are hospital buildings still used today as the center of Toulouse’s medical administration. Very few cars pass over the two bridges besides the ambulances, whose bright blue lights reflect off of the Garonne’s surface. The buildings are curved, so from my angle, it’s as though I’m looking through a fish eye lens. The dome to the right is undergoing some reconstruction, with the far left side covered in scaffolding. It was only until about 30 years ago that this was home to the maternity center in Toulouse.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, the gears in my jetlagged brain started working again and I sent out 76 emails. Some to mentors I wanted to reconnect with and some to prospective farms I would like to visit. Initially, I found farm contacts on Yelp, Facebook, or by reading papers of researchers who visited farms. However I found an excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bienvenue-a-la-ferme.com/recherche/produits-fermiers/2651/?q=&amp;amp;categorie_produit[1]=4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collection&lt;/a&gt; where farms list their visitation times, types of dairy products, and contact info. I am not sure how active farmers are in responding to email envoys from this website, but I am optimistic the 20+ emails will yield some response. Additionally, I planned which days I would attend the two main Toulouse farmers markets, and contacted some cheese shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sampling&quot;&gt;Sampling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I went to the Saint-Aubin Market just a few blocks from my studio. It was so wonderful! Dozens of vendors were set up around the church, from bread, to street food, to produce. There were a few dairy vendors, ranging from the one-person show with cheese in a hacked cooler on a trailer, to whole food truck-style stands with five people working it. To connect with local cheese and yogurt producers, I wrote a script in French that I was planning on showing to them in case we could not converse in English. It included questions about how long they fermented for, if they used starter, and information about their location and milk. I think I was a bit over-enthusiastic here, and did not end up having these conversations with the four producers I bought from that day. A couple were too busy, one waived off the conversation, and the last was packing up to leave when I caught them. This is completely understandable – I realize the information I’m asking for, with my broken French, goes above and beyond the sale of the item. I am still working out ways on how to best approach this, and hope my meeting with a local cheesemaker on Tuesday may help me clarify this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img7.jpeg#full&quot; alt=&quot;Cheese display&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sampled seven regional cheeses, six of which are made from raw (unpasteurized) milk, meaning they should have microbes beyond the starter. Ideally, I would be able to sequence the milk first, to see how the community changes over the course of fermentation. This may be a possibility in the future. Later that day, I &lt;em&gt;sampled&lt;/em&gt; them as well, as I was packaging them to take to lab. They were all delicious! Although I am not a fan of blue cheese, the Roquefort was less heinous to me than other blue cheeses. This cheese is made in caves about an hour away from Toulouse. The fungus &lt;em&gt;Penicillium roqueforti&lt;/em&gt; is responsible for the fascinating blue mold growth, and I should see this microbe loud and clear in the sequencing data. I will be keeping a log of all samples (and likely some eventual metadata visualizations) in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lianamerk.github.io/cultures/Sample-Tracker/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sample Tracker tab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211205/img8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Samples ready&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cultures/2021/12/05/first-week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cultures/2021/12/05/first-week/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-the-scene&quot;&gt;Setting the Scene&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all of my friends and family who have been by my side over the past few months, I thank you endlessly. I have leaned on many of you and it means the world to have such support from those around me. I was planning on leaving in August 2021, and had seven countries where I had developed contacts and relationships in. Under Fellowship guidelines, I could only have countries that were on level one or level two on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/traveladvisories.html/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;US Travel Advisory.&lt;/a&gt; In July, there were only a few countries below the threshold. During this time, I began planning for Bulgaria, which then rose to level three in August. I switched my focus to the Czech Republic, which rose to level three in September. The constant shift in the COVID landscape made it extremely difficult to pin down a path forward. There was the entirely real possibility that I booked airfare, accommodations, committed to join a lab, and the day before my departure, the country could rise to level three, barring my entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, in October, the Watson increased the limit to level three as long as the only reason the country was elevated was due to COVID. I was lucky to find a mentor in France, Prof. Jean-Yves Bouet, who was willing to host me, and got clearance from the Watson to leave early November. At that point, my timeline was quite rushed to plan everything and say goodbye. Additionally, I did not want to miss my cousin’s wedding at end of November. I decided to begin on November 29th, and set all of the wheels in motion to embark!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2020, I formed a collaboration with a biotechnology company for the DNA extraction resources. With the delays and shifts in my project, this fell through. I was lucky enough to form a partnership with Qiagen in November 2021, and will be sure to link their posts about my project on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a likely excessive deep dive into my methods behind packing, keep reading. I wanted to include this for anyone planning a long trip or just genuinely curious about what went into this. In November, I packed and unpacked my belongings four or five times. Because my project is 1/3 shorter than it was originally planned for, I still want to see and sample from as many countries as possible, while getting enough time to immerse myself in the culture. I decided to spend about one month in each country, and thus needed to pack relatively lightly for all of the transit that would be occurring. Additionally, my travels will span virtually all climates – from Iceland in the dead of winter to Greece in the summer. I started with 68 items of clothing and five pairs of shoes. I tested two rolling duffel sizes, 70 liter and 100 liter. Initially, the 100L barely fit. I realized this was not going to work out – it was simply too unwieldy for me to handle. I cut down my closet to 32 items of clothing and four pairs of shoes. This was easier to manage, and left even a little room in the 70L once I optimized my packing method. I tested two brands of normal packing cubes and six types of compression packing cubes, with either folding or rolling the clothes, and found that army rolling into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07Z3NVWYP/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;these Gonex ones&lt;/a&gt; worked the best for me. For the bulkier jackets and sweaters, I used roll-up compression bags that did wonders to free up space in the bag. At some point, after winter, I will likely ship a box of winter clothes home in exchange for light warm weather clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-big-depart&quot;&gt;The big depart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few days at home were a whirlwind of getting documents in order, wedding festivities (congratulations again Stephanie and George!), and booking an Airbnb. Yes, I waited until one week before. This was in the event that France rose to level four during November. Also because I sometimes occasionally procrastinate. On Sunday, November 28th, I cherished the last full day of living in San Diego with my parents. We hit the classics, in-n-out and Pizza Port, and played our favorite family game together – Splendor. I said goodbye to my cats, shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211129/cats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bye cats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to my SCOBY, I hope mom keeps you alive my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cultures/assets/images/20211129/Scoob.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scoob&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, November 29th, I boarded my flight at 11:30 AM PT. I landed at 2 PM on Tuesday, Nov 30 in Toulouse, France! Stay tuned for more on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cultures/2021/11/29/the-beginning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cultures/2021/11/29/the-beginning/</guid>
        
        <category>Transit</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
